https://github.com/nicktruby

hello! I am nick truby and this is me...

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicktruby



https://www.truby.io



In the midst of a career change, recently completed a 12 week intensive software development course at _nology, I am now seeking to secure my first role as a junior software developer.

I'd like to work in software development as I believe it is a career that will make the best use of my personal talents, I enjoy the problem solving aspect and also have a passion for being creative with visual design too. I'm motivated to develop these future skills so I can grow in a career that is exciting and will change and adapt itself over time, giving me ample opportunity to always be learning new things.

My career background is as a successful leader within John Lewis plc, practising empowered leadership and managing the customer journey & experience through visual merchandising, store design and operations.



_nology

I made the commitment to this 12 week intensive software development course at _nology so that I could take my passion for tech, and turn it into a career by learning and embedding a solid foundation of software development skills.

This enabled to me to start coding the right way with modern coding techniques/frameworks and helped me avoid picking up bad or outdated practices.

The curriculum gave me structure to progressively build my knowledge, primarily centred around Javascript & React, and was tailored around building projects to demonstrate those skills. Most importantly, the opportunity to work on a real-client project.

For the client project, in 5 weeks we built a "Shift Reporter" web application for managing a mining workforce and fleet of vehicles. I worked in a team of 8, using agile development and the Scrum framework, working in weekly sprints and pair-programming. I also had the opportunity to start the project as team-leader, setting up the first sprint, running daily stand-ups, communicating with the clients / product owner and presenting our progress at the end of the week.

tech stack

- ReactJS, Javascript ES6, SASS (SCSS), CSS3, HTML5
- Unit testing (Jest & Enzyme)
- Google Firebase (BaaS) Authorisation & Authentication, Firestore Document Database, Hosting
- Rest APIs using NodeJS & Express
- · Git & Github, Agile, Scrum, Pair programming

experience



NHS

<u>Trainee Software Developer</u> | _nology | (Sept 2020 to Dec 2020) see *left*

<u>Customer Service Advisor</u> | Sitel - NHS Test & Trace | May 2020 to present

NHS Test and Trace Programme. Full remote work from home using AWS software. Valuable time management experience as I balanced supporting my family with an income whilst investing full time education training at _nology.

Operations & Visual Merchandising Manager | John Lewis | Sept 2011 to May 2020

Deliver and influence brand image & customer experience through market leading store design, layout and presentation standards. Create the conditions for empowered individuals to thrive, coach and develop others (personal development, performance management, talent & succession planning). Set direction and lead the delivery of a safe, legal and compliant operation (H&S, Facilities, Logistics). Deliver commercial outcomes through driving sales and managing costs. Role model an outstanding internal/external customer experience through a customer focused team, delivering excellence in service and shopkeeping. Chair the democratic function to unlock the potential for 120 Partners' opinion to shape and influence business performance. Manage multiple external stakeholders (Visual Merchandising, Logistics, Buying & Merchandising, Brands/Suppliers, Facilities).

<u>Deputy Store Manager</u> | Halfords (*Jul 2005 - Sept 2011*)

Deputise for store manager including sole site responsibility. Lead a sales team to drive profit through exemplary sales and service. Regionally train and develop across a network of store teams in safe and legal mechanical skills (Bike maintenance and repair, Child seat safety & fitting, Automobile parts).

references

E/N: 81286376 https://www.johnlewispartnership.co.uk/meta/employee-reference.html
Robert Holder - Branch Manager JL Tamworth - holderrobert123@gmail.com
Neil Smith - Line Report JL Tamworth - hellesmith@outlook.com

about

I enjoy solving problems, I'm a very logical thinking person, and that's just how I like to approach things in life. As a child I borrowed a logic problems puzzle book my father took on holiday and I struggled to convince him at the time that I wasn't just looking the answers up in the back. As I've progressed through different jobs in my career, I've found this is the key skill that drives my success.

I'm very competitive and I strive to be the best at whatever I put my mind too, I'm an ambitious person and I'd like to progress my career to a senior level. Under both my employers I've shown strong progression in my time with them.

My development into leadership has taught me a wide array of soft skills, and the effectiveness of a high performing team that supports and develops each other. I'm a team player that values the strengths of others and how to connect, calibrate and contribute together. Working in a democratic business, and as an elected representative I've also learnt the ability to use team opinion to shape and influence business decision making and unlock the empowerment of individuals.

family

I am due to be married to my fiancé, Sally, in 2022. This was due to be in 2021 but we decided to push it back a year when Covid cast some uncertainty over our savings plan and how long the country will have restrictions imposed. But we are still very much looking forward to our special day and we both love to travel so probably the honeymoon even more!

We have a son, Arthur William Truby, who is currently 18 months old. He is a large motivation in life for me, I want to have a career I can be proud of, and provide for my family. We enjoy going on days out and are national trust members, Arthur is just starting to get more confident with his walking & recently started going to Nursery too.

We live in Tamworth in the midlands, and we have family in Bristol, Swansea and Yeovil, so we often get together in Bristol as it is the epicentre of us all.

interests

Ever since my first mechanical experiences working at Halfords, I always enjoyed working with my hands. I still keep up bicycle mechanics as a hobby, but more commonly use my hands with any DIY project I can get stuck into. Most recently I took on the challenge of refitting our bathroom.

I've always had an interest in tech. I bought my first Mac in 2005 and have been a Mac person ever since, this started my enjoyment with computer media and I did a bit of professional video editing in the past. I've taken apart and serviced many personal electronics in the past, and enjoy understanding how things are made.

I also like video gaming, I'm a console gamer and have recently made the switch to next generation with the PS5. I'm a completionism and enjoy trophy hunting on single player RPG games, and play online mostly on Call of Duty zombies and battle royale.

I also enjoy TV and Cinema, I'm a bit of a Star Wars nerd, but not quite to the cos play level!

education

2009-2010 | NVQ Level 2 Traineeship - Customer Service

2008-2009 | NVQ Level 2 Traineeship - Mechanical Engineering (Cytech - Cycle Mechanic)

Apple Certified Professional |
New Technology Institute
(City of Birmingham University)
16/01/2008 |
FCP101 | Final Cut Pro 6 : Level 1
04/06/2008 |
FCP300 | Final Cut Pro 6 : Level 2
12/11/2008 |
MOT101 | Motion 3 : Level 1
15/10/2008 |
COL101 | Color : Level 1
03/04/2009 |
DVDSP101 | DVD Studio Pro : Level 1
15/05/2009 |
STP101 | Soundtrack Pro 2 : Level 1

2004-2006 | 6th Form (A-Levels) | Mathematics, I.C.T (Information Communication Technology), Theatre Studies

1999-2004 | Wilnecote High School (GCSE's), Maths, Science, I.C.T, Geography, English, French, Drama.